<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB"
                xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Configuring the Metrics Agent</title>
    <conbody>
                <section>
                        <p>The installation of the Metrics Agent includes its initial configuration. To prepare the environment for application operators, you have to reconfigure the agent. It is necessary to explicitly activate the libvirt metrics that the application operators use for monitoring. </p>
                        <p>To reconfigure the agent, proceed as follows:</p>
                        <ol
                            compact="no">
                                <li>
                                        <p>Activate the libvirt metrics. For details, refer to <xref
                                                        href="../install/c-install-metricsagent-enh.xml"
                                                        />. For an example configuration, refer to the information on <codeph>libvirt.yml</codeph> in <xref
                                                        href="../appendix/r-metricsadditional.xml"/>.</p>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                        <p>Make sure that the host name specified for the <codeph>nova-compute</codeph> service is specified as value for the <codeph>hostname</codeph> parameter in the <codeph>agent.yaml</codeph> configuration file.</p>
                                        <p>For this purpose, check the host name for the <codeph>nova-compute</codeph> service in your environment first. You can execute the following command: </p>
                                        <codeblock># nova service-list</codeblock>
                                        <p>The <codeph>Host</codeph> column in the <codeph>nova-compute</codeph> line shows the host name for the <codeph>nova-compute</codeph> service in your environment.</p>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                        <p>To check the <codeph>hostname</codeph> parameter in the <codeph>agent.yaml</codeph> configuration file, open the file with your favorite editor.</p>
                                        <p>Example:</p>
                                        <codeblock>sudo vim /etc/monasca/agent/agent.yaml</codeblock>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                        <p>If the <codeph>hostname</codeph> parameter does not correspond to the host name for the <codeph>nova-compute</codeph> service in your environment (see Step 2), update it.</p>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                        <p>To start the agent again, execute the following command:</p>
                                        <codeblock>sudo systemctl start monasca-agent	</codeblock>
                                </li>
                        </ol>
            <p>As soon as the agent is started again, it is available with the updated configuration settings. The application operators can instantly use the libvirt metrics for monitoring.</p>
                </section>
        </conbody>
</concept>
