<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB"
            xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Defining Notifications</title>
    <conbody>
        <section
                            id="Notifications_define_how_user_concept_conbody_section">
            <p>Notifications define how users are informed when a threshold value defined for an alarm is reached or exceeded. In an alarm definition, you can assign one or multiple notifications.</p>
            <p>For a notification, you specify the following elements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol>. A unique identifier of the notification. The name is offered for selection when defining an alarm.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p><uicontrol>Type</uicontrol>. The notification method to be used. <codeph>Email</codeph>, <codeph>Slack</codeph>, or <codeph>WebHook</codeph> can be selected provided that the methods were enabled when installing the Monitoring Service. </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p><uicontrol>Address</uicontrol>. </p>
                    <p>For <codeph>Email</codeph>, the email address to be notified when an alarm is triggered.</p>
                    <p>
                        <note othertype="note"
                                >Generic top-level domains such as business domain names are not supported in email addresses (for example <codeph>user@xyz.company</codeph>).</note>
                    </p>
                    <!--p>For <codeph>HipChat</codeph>, the URL specifying the room to which the notification is to be sent. Example URL with variables for the room ID and access token: <codeph>https://api.hipchat.com/v2/room/&lt;room_id>/notification?auth_token=&lt;access_token></codeph></p -->
                    <!--p>For <codeph>Jira</codeph>, TODO. </p -->
                    <!--p>For <codeph>PagerDuty</codeph>, the PagerDuty Service API Key to be notified when an alarm is triggered. </p -->
                    <p>For <codeph>Slack</codeph>, the URL specifying the channel to which the notification is to be sent. Example URL with variables for the legacy token and the channel: </p>
                    <p><codeph>https://slack.com/api/chat.postMessage?token=&lt;token>&amp;channel=#&lt;channel></codeph></p>
                    <p>For <codeph>WebHook</codeph>, the WebHook URL to be loaded when an alarm is triggered. </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p><uicontrol>Period</uicontrol>. For <codeph>WebHook</codeph> only. The integer value indicates how often a notification is to be resent.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>To create, edit, and delete notifications, use <uicontrol>Monitoring &gt; Notifications</uicontrol>.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
