<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Installation</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>The installation of <ph conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> comprises the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
                <li>
                    <p>Preparing the installation environment as well as the software and setup utilities.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Installing the Monitoring Service. It is recommended that you use a dedicated physical machine for the Monitoring Service which meets the requirements outlined in the next section. It is not recommended that there are any other services running on the machine.</p>
                    <note othertype="note">
                        <p>For <ph conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> in productive operation, do not install the Monitoring Service on a virtual machine. <ph
                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> has demanding hardware requirements that are not met by a virtual machine. In addition, neighboring virtual machines may cause trouble.</p>
                    </note>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Preparing the integration of the Monitoring Service with your OpenStack platform.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Installing the OpenStack extensions to integrate the Monitoring Service with the OpenStack platform. This includes the installation of agents for monitoring your OpenStack services and servers as well as the installation of the Horizon Plugin required for accessing the monitoring functions from the OpenStack Horizon dashboard.</p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
