<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB"
                xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Installing a Metrics Agent on the OpenStack Platform </title>
    <conbody>
        <!-- section><p>OSP10 Integration Point - Metrics Agent based on OpenStack Pike / self-extracting installer</p>
<p>Help? monasca-agent/main.py at master openstack/monasca-agent</p></section -->
        <!--section>
            <p><i><b>NOTE TO REVIEWERS</b>: </i><i>Do we support <b>all</b> parameters listed in https://github.com/openstack/monasca-agent/blob/master/docs/Agent.md#monasca-setup-recommended ? </i></p>
            <p><i>In CMM 1.1, we explicitly documented that the dimensions parameter was not supported: "The dimensions parameter is not supported by CMM. The installer auto-detects applications and processes that are running on your machine and saves the corresponding settings to the agent's configuration file. Additional dimensions cannot be specified." </i></p>
        </section-->
        <section>
            <p>For monitoring OpenStack services in your environment, you need to install a Metrics Agent on the OpenStack node on which the  services are running. The agent installer performs the following tasks:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>It automatically configures the agent to retrieve metrics data from the server and send the data to the Monitoring Service for further processing.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>It automatically activates system metrics for monitoring the OpenStack services and the server on which they are running. The metrics include system checks, for example, on CPU usage, disk space, or the average system load. No manual configuration is required for these checks.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>As enhancement to the system metrics, the installer auto-detects applications and OpenStack processes that are running on the server. The corresponding metrics are automatically configured. No manual configuration is required.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>The agent installer creates all configuration files required for monitoring. They include the following:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p><codeph>agent.yaml</codeph> located in the <codeph>/etc/monasca/agent</codeph> directory.</p>
                    <p>It defines the agent configuration. </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p><codeph>*.yaml</codeph> files located in the <codeph>/etc/monasca/agent/conf.d</codeph> directory. </p>
                    <p>They provide the metrics the agent uses for monitoring. A <codeph>*.yaml</codeph> file is provided for each set of system metrics and for the additional metrics used to monitor the specific applications and OpenStack processes that are auto-detected. The <codeph>*.yaml</codeph> files store the configuration information that is auto-detected during the installation process. </p>
                    <p>For details on the system metrics and the additional metrics, refer to <xref
                            href="../appendix/r-metricsintro.xml"/>.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p><codeph>*.yaml</codeph> files located in the <codeph>/opt/monasca-agent/share/monasca/agent/conf.d</codeph> directory. </p>
                    <p>They provide metrics that you can activate as enhancement to the metrics that are automatically provided with the agent installation. These files provide template configurations that you can adapt to your environment.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>The installation of an agent includes its initial configuration. This ensures that comprehensive metrics data for monitoring services and servers is retrieved. </p>
            <p>Options are also provided for reconfiguring an agent following a successful installation. If required, you can update the <codeph>agent.yaml</codeph> file, and you can activate metrics in addition to the ones that are automatically provided with the installation. </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
