<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Installation</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>The installation of <ph conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> comprises the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
                <li>
                    <p>Preparing the installation environment.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Preparing the integration of <ph
                            conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> with your OpenStack platform.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Installing the Monitoring Service. </p>
                    <p>The installation of the Monitoring Service is based on Docker. Production-ready Docker images are provided for the services that make up the Monitoring Service. Instances of these images run in separate Docker containers as soon as the installation is successful. </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Installing a Metrics Agent. </p>
                    <p>A Metrics Agent is installed as an extension to your OpenStack platform for monitoring an OpenStack service and the server on which it is deployed.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Installing a Log Agent. </p>
                    <p>A Log Agent is installed as an extension to your OpenStack platform for managing the logs of an OpenStack service and the server on which it is deployed.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Installing the Horizon Plugin. </p>
                    <p>The Horizon Plugin is installed as an extension to your OpenStack platform. It is required for accessing the monitoring and log management functions of <ph
                            conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> from OpenStack Horizon. </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </section>
        <section>
            <p>The following picture depicts a simplified installation scenario with a <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> node and one OpenStack node only: </p>
            <fig>
                <image alt="installation-br.png" height="90" href="../../images/installation-br.png" width="200"/>
            </fig>
            <p>Observe the following when installing <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>It is recommended that you use a dedicated physical machine as a  <ph
                            conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> node which meets the requirements outlined in the next section. It is not recommended that there are any other services running on the machine.</p>
                    <note othertype="note">
                        <p>The Monitoring Service can be installed on a virtual machine. For <ph
                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> in productive operation, however, keep in mind that <ph
                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> has demanding hardware requirements that are not met by a virtual machine. In addition, neighboring virtual machines may cause trouble.</p>
                    </note>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>The installation of the Monitoring Service automatically includes the installation of a Metrics Agent and a Log Agent for monitoring <ph
                            conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>The Horizon Plugin must be installed on the node where the OpenStack Horizon Service is deployed.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>A productive OpenStack environment consists of multiple OpenStack nodes on which multiple services are running. You can install the agents on any OpenStack node where a service to be monitored is deployed. </p>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
