<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB"
                            xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Installation</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>To install a Log Agent, proceed as follows:</p>
            <ol compact="no">
                <li>
                    <p>Log in to the OpenStack node on which to install the Log Agent.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Prepare an installation directory. </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Extract the <codeph>CMM_client_2.0.2.zip</codeph> archive file from the <ph
                            conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> installation package to the installation directory. The archive provides the following files:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li><codeph>log-agent-CMM_2.0.2.run</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>monasca-agent-CMM_2.0.2.run</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>monasca-ui-CMM_2.0.2.run</codeph></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Change the access permission of the <codeph>log-agent-CMM_2.0.2.run</codeph> file to Execute.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Make sure that your <codeph>/root/.my.cnf</codeph> file does not define any passwords in single quotes.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Run the agent installer, and provide the required OpenStack Keystone credentials. </p>
                    <p>Example: </p>
                    <codeblock>./log-agent-CMM_2.0.2.run \
    --target "/opt/monasca/monasca-log-agent" -- \
    --monasca_log_api_url "&lt;cmm_ip>" \   
    --keystone_auth_url "&lt;openstack_ip>" \   
    --project_name "&lt;project>" \
    --username "&lt;user_name>"  \
    --password "&lt;password>" \
    --user_domain_name "default" \
    --project_domain_name "default" \
    --hostname "['&lt;name>:'&lt;dimension>']" \
    "/var/log/*" "/var/log/monasca/api/error.log"</codeblock>
                    <p><i>##TODO CHECK: default values, mandatory, optional## </i></p>
                    <p>All parameters are filled with default values. Each value must be enclosed in double quotes (<codeph>"</codeph>). The minimum set of parameters that must be configured for an agent includes: </p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            <p><codeph>--target</codeph>. The directory in which the agent is installed.<i> ##mandatory##</i></p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <p><codeph>--monasca_log_api_url</codeph>. The URL used to access the server where the Monitoring Service is installed. Example: <codeph>http://192.168.1.6:5607/v3.0</codeph>.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <p><codeph>--keystone_auth_url</codeph>. The URL used to access the server where the OpenStack Keystone service is installed. The service is used for authenticating the user specified in <codeph>username</codeph>. It must be a V3 endpoint. Example: <codeph>http://192.168.1.5:35357/v3</codeph>.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <p><codeph>--project_name</codeph>. The name of the OpenStack project for which log data is to be retrieved by the agent. Example: <codeph>monasca</codeph>.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <p><codeph>--username</codeph>. The user to be used for authenticating the agent against Keystone, for example <codeph>monasca-agent</codeph>.</p>
                            <p>The user specified here must have the <codeph>monasca-agent</codeph> role in OpenStack and be assigned to the OpenStack project that is to be monitored by the agent. The project is specified in <codeph>project_name</codeph>.</p>
                            <p>It is recommended that this user is used only for configuration purposes and not for actually monitoring services and servers.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <p><codeph>--password</codeph>. The password of the user specified in <codeph>username</codeph>.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <p><codeph>--user_domain_name</codeph>. Optional. The user domain name to be used for user name scoping. <i>If not specified, what does <codeph>default</codeph> imply?</i></p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <p><codeph>project_domain_name</codeph>. Optional. The project domain name used for authenticating the agent against OpenStack Keystone. <i>If not specified, what does <codeph>default</codeph> imply?</i></p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <p><codeph>--hostname</codeph>. Optional. Meta information to be collected with the log data that is retrieved by the agent. The information can be defined as an array. Example: <codeph>['service:monitoring', 'hostname:node1']</codeph>. <i>Optional?</i></p>
                            <p>The meta information defined by a dimension is attached to each log entry. It is represented as one or more fields in the log management window. For the user who is working with the log data, dimensions provide additional filtering options.</p>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ol>
            <!--p>##TODO For detailed information on the configuration parameters that can be defined, refer to ##</p -->
            <p>For running the installer, it is not mandatory to specify input file paths. Yet, without specifying which data is to be retrieved, an immediate update of the agent configuration is required following the installation.</p>
            <p>Specify the input file paths as in the following example: </p>
            <codeblock>"/var/log/monasca/api/error.log" "/var/log/neutron/firewall.log"</codeblock>
            <p>The installer creates a <codeph>monasca-log-agent.service</codeph> file in the <codeph>/etc/systemd/system</codeph> directory, and automatically runs the service file to start the agent. </p>
            <p>The agent is provided as a LINUX service. A startup script is created that automatically starts the agent each time the machine is booted. </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
