<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB"
                xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Creating Projects, Users, and Roles</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>To integrate <ph conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> with the OpenStack Keystone service, specific preparations must manually be taken in OpenStack Keystone. </p>
            <p>You have to create a project, a user, and the required roles. The project, the user and the roles must exist before you proceed with installing the Monitoring Service.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating a Project </title>
            <p>A dedicated OpenStack project must be prepared for <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />. The monitoring data retrieved for <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> and your OpenStack services and servers is accessible to users assigned to this project, provided they have the required role assigned.</p>
            <p>Example:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>openstack project create monasca </codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating Roles</title>
            <p>The following OpenStack roles must be prepared:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p><codeph>monasca-user</codeph>. This role must be assigned to any user who wants to perform monitoring and log management tasks.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p><codeph>monasca-agent</codeph>. This role must be assigned to the user used for authenticating the Metrics Agent and the Log Agent against OpenStack Keystone.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>Example:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>openstack role create monasca-user
openstack role create monasca-agent</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating a User</title>
            <p>An OpenStack user must be prepared that is used for authenticating an agent against OpenStackKeystone. The user must be specified in the agent configuration. The user must have the <codeph>monasca-agent</codeph> role in OpenStack and be assigned to the OpenStack project that is to be monitored by the agent. </p>
            <p>This user is used by the Metrics Agent and the Log Agent to submit data to the Monitoring Service. It is recommended that this user is used only for configuration purposes and not for actually monitoring services and servers. </p>
            <p>Example:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>openstack user create --project monasca \
  --password password monasca-agent</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Assigning Roles </title>
            <p>The following assigments must be prepared:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>The new OpenStack user (<codeph>monasca-agent</codeph> in the example) must be assigned to the project prepared for <ph
                            conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> and must have the <codeph>monasca-agent</codeph> role in this project.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <!--p>##required for communication with API</p-->
                    <p>The OpenStack <codeph>admin</codeph> user must be assigned to the project prepared for <ph
                            conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> and must have the <codeph>monasca-user</codeph> and <codeph>admin</codeph> roles in this project.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>Example: </p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>openstack role add --project monasca --user monasca-agent monasca-agent
openstack role add --project monasca --user admin monasca-user
openstack role add --project monasca --user admin admin</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
